Robin K

• 9789762942 • liorobin5@gmail.com • Chennai, IN • Github • LinkedIn • Portfolio

SUMMARY

Software development professional offering 2.5 years of related experience with extensive Full Stack
 Development experience in developing and designing web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript,
 React, Node.js, Django, Azure. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements.

KEY SKILLS

JavaScript, CSS, React, React-Query, Next.js, Redux, Node.js, Django Framework, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, API Design, Graph QL, Docker, Microsoft, Azure, AWS, Git,

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MathCo, Bangalore | Remote

Jul 2022 - Present

Associate - Product Engineering

- Engineered 3+ web applications, created dynamic and reusable UI web interfaces using React Framework,
 Redux, and React-Query, Apollo GraphQL client ensuring design consistency across platforms
- Reduced application load time by 40% through caching and performance enhancements and streamlined user experience
- Enhanced data flow by integrating front-end components with REST API and GraphQL endpoints
- Written unit tests using **Jest** and React Testing Library to maintain code quality standards.
- Designed REST APIs and GraphQL Endpoint using Node.js/Django interacting with NoSQL/SQL databases
- Enabled role-based access control through Azure Active Directory Groups by **integrating Azure Single Sign-On (SSO)**, ensuring secure authorization workflows
- Monitored and Analyzed user interactions in real-time with **Azure Application Insights** and React frontend
- Devised Azure Logic App workflow automating access approval emails, expediting processes leading to a 60% reduction in approval time and enhanced security
- Built CI(Build) and CD(Release) pipelines using Docker Containers in Azure DevOps for **deploying the Azure App services**
- **Automated** Django(Python) script to run a CRON job in Serverless Azure Function weekly to load dataset into PostgreSQL Server, **increasing data loading efficiency by 98%**

Skiya Technologies | Chennai

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022

Developer

Responsibilities:

- Primarily focused on front-end development, developing responsive and visually engaging web user interfaces using **React.js**, **Next.js**, **React-Query** (for data-fetching and caching)
- Developed reusable UI components with consistent design using Chakra UI
- Designed **Node.js/Express.js APIs** interacting with **PostgreSQL** database server
- Seamlessly integrated with API endpoints for enhanced user interactions

TRAINING

GUVI GEEK NETWORK | Chennai,TN

Aug 2021 - Jan 2022

Intern - Full Stack Development

- Project based Full Stack Development Program in MERN
- Knowledge on developer tools such as Git and deploying web applications onto web servers.
- Deeper understanding of Frontend web development by developing highly responsive web apps
- Designing backend web development by building performant APIs using Node.js and MongoDB
- Deploying web apps to PaaS providers such as Netlify, Render linked with Git repository

PROJECTS

Oct 2021 - Jan 2022

Shoptronics - Ecommerce Application

Developed an Ecommerce application using React.js, Node.js with Express framework, and MongoDB.

Built interactive and responsive UI design for desktop and mobile platforms, integrating React-Redux and Redux-

Persist state management to enhance user experience and optimize application performance.

Implemented E2E functionalities like **Browsing Products**, **User Registration/Login**, **Cart Management**,

Wishlist, Order Creation, Admin Dashboard and Payment Integration using RazorPay.

Built a **secure authentication system** with Login with Mobile and Email, User Registration

Enabled smooth password reset flows for improved user convenience and implemented **email notifications** for triggered events like Order Confirmation, Password Reset, OTP flows, etc..

Integrated **Razor Pay API for secure payment processing** and a seamless checkout experience.

Designed an **Admin portal with role-based authentication** to handle inventory, orders, and store management, implemented protected routes for admin login, ensuring secure access control.

Incorporated Google OAuth2.0 Single Sign-on for additional simplified user engagement

Deployed URL - https://shoptronics-ecom.netlify.app/

EDUCATION

SASTRA Deemed To Be University | Tanjore, TN

Jul 2015 - Jun 2019

Bachelor Of Technology in Mechanical Engineering

PERSONAL PROFILE

• Date of Birth: **01-08-1997**

• Nationality: Indian

• Gender: Male

• Languages: English, Tamil, Hindi